<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GameMaker on Derme's Coffee</title><link>https://derme.coffee/categories/gamemaker/</link><description>Recent content in GameMaker on Derme's Coffee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 08:30:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://derme.coffee/categories/gamemaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cookie - Stop GameMaker deleting skins when updating</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-06-08-cookie-stop-gamemaker-deleting-skins-when-updating/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 08:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-06-08-cookie-stop-gamemaker-deleting-skins-when-updating/</guid><description>GameMaker&amp;rsquo;s auto-updater has its issues, but deleting your customs skins shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be one of them.
One of GameMaker&amp;rsquo;s hidden features is that it has two folders on your computer. The first folder stores the main program that gets overwritten when you update. The second folder is where you can keep all your skins, tutorials, extensions and DnD libraries safe from the evil auto-muncher.
So the folder where the main components of the IDE are is located at</description></item><item><title>Cookie - Surfaces in GameMaker: Studio</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-05-31-surfaces-in-gamemaker-studio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 02:25:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-05-31-surfaces-in-gamemaker-studio/</guid><description>Getting started with drawing to a surface in GameMaker can be scary, especially when you see all the warnings and mystical properties that are associated with them.
The good news is that in reality, there isn&amp;rsquo;t really that much to them. In the latest release of GameMaker 1.3 the main draw area IS a surface. So you&amp;rsquo;re working with them already, you just don&amp;rsquo;t know it.
The main thing you have to remember about surfaces is they aren&amp;rsquo;t guaranteed to be there, just like biscuits in a biscuit jar, so you have to check they exist before drawing (or eating).</description></item><item><title>Just 21 - Release</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-03-01-just-21-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 03:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-03-01-just-21-release/</guid><description>‘Just 21&amp;rsquo; is a game I started working during the middle of last year as a mobile HTML5 game, however I hit a couple technical difficulties at the time and set the project aside. I recently came back and re-worked the project for Android and iOS. At this stage I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on releasing a HTML5 version, though it certainly is a possibility for the future.
        When updating the game I thought that by using the existing codebase I wrote last year would help save time, which in hindsight was a mistake.</description></item><item><title>GameMaker: ThreeJS Extension Demo!</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-05-15-gamemaker-threejs-extension-demo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-05-15-gamemaker-threejs-extension-demo/</guid><description>Those of you that follow me on Twitter will know that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last week working on integrating the ThreeJS (r58) library with GameMaker: Studio. Now if you are already bursting with excitement you can skip to the end of the post for a link to the working demo!
The most awesome thing about this extension is that you can still do all your input control, AI and GUI though the GameMaker canvas.</description></item><item><title>GMC Game Jam, GooglePlay, Future Projects</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-31-gmc-game-jam-googleplay-future-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-31-gmc-game-jam-googleplay-future-projects/</guid><description>At the start of this week I entered the 9th GameMaker Community Game Jam, my entry wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as it could of been, in the end I only spent a small amount time working on it. However I had a lot of laughs making it and got some really helpful feedback, which I&amp;rsquo;ll take with me when I go into the next Jam in three months.
You can go see the entry here.</description></item><item><title>The Glass is Falling - Update 1.1</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-22-the-glass-is-falling-update-1-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-22-the-glass-is-falling-update-1-1/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>About this time last month I released “The Glass is Falling” via the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Steam Workshop&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> and I received some really good feedback about the game. All of this has gone into creating the update which I uploaded yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>New background and sprites&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Physics Improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Various Bug Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>The Glass is Falling - Release</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-12-23-the-glass-is-falling-release/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 05:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-12-23-the-glass-is-falling-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>‘The Glass is Falling&amp;rsquo; is a game, well more mini-game, that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on in the background for the last week. The goal of the game is simple, stop the glass from hitting the floor. It&amp;rsquo;s available now on the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->GM:S Steam Workshop&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, so if you want to have a play before reading on go ahead!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>It was the first game that I designed &amp;amp; planned before I started development and I was extremely happy when the final product turned out like the concept art.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Game Maker 8.1 Lite</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-16-game-maker-8-1-lite-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 08:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-16-game-maker-8-1-lite-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>GameMaker 8.1 (Single word now) has received mixed reviews on the &lt;a href="http://gmc.yoyogames.com/">Game Maker Community&lt;/a>, while a lot of members have given it thumbs up, many are upset that it has broken their code and is not compatible with certain extensions/DLLs. Personally though not only does it run all my games perfectly, it also runs them a lot faster than &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Game Maker&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> 8.0 (Two Words).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.yoyogames.com/">YoYo Games&lt;/a> made lots of noise about the new zoom feature in the room editor, while this is great (bit buggy though), the big thing new feature for me has to be the upgraded font rendering! Now all my games have sharp as crystal text. When Mike Dailly first brought up the whole font improvement, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t get it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even tell the difference between the two images he put up comparing the new and the old. But now I get it and I am going to rush out and buy the standard edition tomorrow (Literally).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>