<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Derme's Coffee</title><link>https://derme.coffee/</link><description>Recent content on Derme's Coffee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://derme.coffee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[GameMaker] CSV Manager</title><link>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-csv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-csv/</guid><description>GM: HTML is an extension for GameMaker: Studio that makes it possible to add snippets of HTML code to your HTML5 games. It also allows you to connect any elements you create back to your code, so for example you can press a HTML button and make a character jump.</description></item><item><title>[GameMaker] JavaScript3D (J3D)</title><link>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-j3d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-j3d/</guid><description>J3D uses CSS to “stack” the GameMaker generated canvas over a WebGL renderer, this allows you to continue using GameMaker for all your input controls, AI and GUI while being able to use the 3D features of ThreeJS.</description></item><item><title>FrostCube</title><link>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/frostcube/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/frostcube/</guid><description>Founded in 2009, FrostCube is a independent game development team. Developer of &amp;lsquo;The Glass if Falling&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Just 21&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>[GameMaker] CSV Manager</title><link>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-html/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-html/</guid><description>CSV manager allows you to take a .csv file and load it into a GameMaker array. It can also be used to save your GameMaker arrays to .csv files for storage. The asset includes detailed documentation on how to import your database from Excel and get it working. A simple demo to help get you started is also included.</description></item><item><title>[GameMaker] GMY YouTube Pro</title><link>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-youtube/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/gms-youtube/</guid><description>This extension allows access to the YouTube API functions. This allows you to know exactly what state the video is in (playing, paused, ended). This means that you know when to resume the gameplay as you can find out when the video has finished.</description></item><item><title>[Unity] Simple Car Demo</title><link>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/unity-car/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/portfolio/unity-car/</guid><description>Provides a WheelSet class (A fancy wrapper for Unity&amp;rsquo;s built in WheelColiders). This class does a lot of the heavy lifting for you and lets you focus on just getting the car moving how you want it to.</description></item><item><title>Level 19 - Homeworld Remastered</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2015-02-26-level-19-homeworld-remastered/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 12:52:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2015-02-26-level-19-homeworld-remastered/</guid><description>I have not been excited for a video game release for quite some time, but when this was announced I was excited.
When I played the original Homeworld in 1999 I loved it, even though I could never get past the 6thmission at the time, it’s a game that’s stuck with me since.
This game with the new engine is simply stunning. The visuals are incredible, the cut scenes are re-mastered and the sound quality is excellent.</description></item><item><title>Unicolour</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-09-06-unicolour/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 16:23:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-09-06-unicolour/</guid><description>With the shut down of Twitpic I decided it was time to upload my GIFs somewhere else, all one of them. Unfortunately Twitter doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow GIFs over 3MB, so I had to upload it to YouTube instead, but better than it being lost forever.</description></item><item><title>Mint - Preview of the new 'Blue' Steam UI</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-08-13-mint-preview-of-the-new-blue-steam-ui/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 02:17:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-08-13-mint-preview-of-the-new-blue-steam-ui/</guid><description>The Steam Database posted some mock-ups of what the Steam store will look like with the new theme that is currently in development. Out of curiosity I wanted to know what the whole thing would look like inside the updated client (that is currently available in the beta channel).
All over I think when it&amp;rsquo;s finished it&amp;rsquo;ll be a nice improvement over the current one which is, in my opinion, a little ugly but immeasurably better than what it used to look like.</description></item><item><title>Cookie - Stop GameMaker deleting skins when updating</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-06-08-cookie-stop-gamemaker-deleting-skins-when-updating/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 08:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-06-08-cookie-stop-gamemaker-deleting-skins-when-updating/</guid><description>GameMaker&amp;rsquo;s auto-updater has its issues, but deleting your customs skins shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be one of them.
One of GameMaker&amp;rsquo;s hidden features is that it has two folders on your computer. The first folder stores the main program that gets overwritten when you update. The second folder is where you can keep all your skins, tutorials, extensions and DnD libraries safe from the evil auto-muncher.
So the folder where the main components of the IDE are is located at</description></item><item><title>Cookie - Surfaces in GameMaker: Studio</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-05-31-surfaces-in-gamemaker-studio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 02:25:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-05-31-surfaces-in-gamemaker-studio/</guid><description>Getting started with drawing to a surface in GameMaker can be scary, especially when you see all the warnings and mystical properties that are associated with them.
The good news is that in reality, there isn&amp;rsquo;t really that much to them. In the latest release of GameMaker 1.3 the main draw area IS a surface. So you&amp;rsquo;re working with them already, you just don&amp;rsquo;t know it.
The main thing you have to remember about surfaces is they aren&amp;rsquo;t guaranteed to be there, just like biscuits in a biscuit jar, so you have to check they exist before drawing (or eating).</description></item><item><title>Just 21 - Release</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-03-01-just-21-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 03:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-03-01-just-21-release/</guid><description>Just 21 is a game I started working during the middle of last year as a mobile HTML5 game, however I hit a couple technical difficulties at the time and set the project aside. I recently came back and re-worked the project for Android and iOS. At this stage I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on releasing a HTML5 version, though it certainly is a possibility for the future.
Initial Prototype
Final mobile HTML5 version</description></item><item><title>Rotated Hexels!</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-11-11-rotated-hexels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-11-11-rotated-hexels/</guid><description>So today I finally decided to pick up Hexels, which is a neat little tool to make minimalistic artwork. However I needed a rotated Hexel for my current project, which needed to be defined via the custom-shape tool. (Thanks to YellowAfterlife for pointing that feature out)
If you need this for one of your projects you can download it here(EDIT 22/5/2014 - Hexels now includes rotated hexels as a preset, you can find it in the custom shape section).</description></item><item><title>GameMaker: ThreeJS Extension Demo!</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-05-15-gamemaker-threejs-extension-demo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-05-15-gamemaker-threejs-extension-demo/</guid><description>Those of you that follow me on Twitter will know that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last week working on integrating the ThreeJS (r58) library with GameMaker: Studio. Now if you are already bursting with excitement you can skip to the end of the post for a link to the working demo!
The most awesome thing about this extension is that you can still do all your input control, AI and GUI though the GameMaker canvas.</description></item><item><title>Level 19 - Chickens and Moles</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-03-05-level-19-chickens-and-moles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 23:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-03-05-level-19-chickens-and-moles/</guid><description>Chickens and Molesis the latest release from the team over at Wormintheworks. The game is available on iOS, Android, Windows Phone, Windows, Mac and Facebook. I ended up scoring myself an iOS promo code.
When I first saw this game all I could think of was Angry Birds, a game which has too many clones these days. However Chickens &amp;amp; Moles is a whole different type of gameplay to that of Angry Birds, one which you find yourself touching the screen to throw boulders at various objects in the hope of rescuing en-caged animals.</description></item><item><title>GMC Game Jam, GooglePlay, Future Projects</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-31-gmc-game-jam-googleplay-future-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-31-gmc-game-jam-googleplay-future-projects/</guid><description>At the start of this week I entered the 9th GameMaker Community Game Jam, my entry wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as it could of been, in the end I only spent a small amount time working on it. However I had a lot of laughs making it and got some really helpful feedback, which I&amp;rsquo;ll take with me when I go into the next Jam in three months.
You can go see the entry here.</description></item><item><title>The Glass is Falling - Update 1.1</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-22-the-glass-is-falling-update-1-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 05:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-22-the-glass-is-falling-update-1-1/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>About this time last month I released “The Glass is Falling” via the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Steam Workshop&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> and I received some really good feedback about the game. All of this has gone into creating the update which I uploaded yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>New background and sprites&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Physics Improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Various Bug Fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>The Glass is Falling - Release</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-12-23-the-glass-is-falling-release/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 05:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-12-23-the-glass-is-falling-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>‘The Glass is Falling&amp;rsquo; is a game, well more mini-game, that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on in the background for the last week. The goal of the game is simple, stop the glass from hitting the floor. It&amp;rsquo;s available now on the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->GM:S Steam Workshop&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, so if you want to have a play before reading on go ahead!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>It was the first game that I designed &amp;amp; planned before I started development and I was extremely happy when the final product turned out like the concept art.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Official Portal 2 Turret? Yes please.</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-09-16-official-portal-2-turret-yes-please/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-09-16-official-portal-2-turret-yes-please/</guid><description>Portal would have to be one of my favourite puzzle games of all time the others being Lemmings and Portal 2.
When Velociraptor proofing my place of dwelling, something I always wanted to include was a couple of Portal turrets, so I&amp;rsquo;m really hoping that Valve plan to start selling them on the adjacent self to the Weighted Companion Cubes.</description></item><item><title>Day One: Nexus 7</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-09-15-day-one-nexus-7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 07:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-09-15-day-one-nexus-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>I decided last week that I needed a tablet to test my upcoming Android app that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on over the last few months. After writing several pro/con lists, I settled on Asus&amp;rsquo; Nexus 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main reason I decided to go with the Nexus 7 for app development was that it is running the newest version of Android (4.1.1) which is brilliant for testing my app. Being the flagship Google Tablet I expect that it will get all the major revisions of Android almost as they are released.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://derme.coffee/uploads/2012/09/google_nexus7.png" alt="Google Nexus 7">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Day in the Life of my Minecraft Server</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-10-18-a-day-in-the-life-of-my-minecraft-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-10-18-a-day-in-the-life-of-my-minecraft-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a big fan of Minecraft, and I probably will never be, which is a little bit strange seeing as I run a Minecraft server. The game just never clicked for me, I always found it a bit, dull. Though I will admit I&amp;rsquo;m a little bit jealous when people go out and build some incredible stuff like a 8-bit computer or a 3d printer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://derme.coffee/uploads/2011/10/Minecraft_Destiny.png" alt="Minecraft Stargate Destiny">
&lt;em>Destiny out of Stargate Universe - By Blade695&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watching that ship getting constructed was absolutely epic, it even has a gate on it! Only thing it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do is jump to FTL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://derme.coffee/uploads/2011/10/Minecraft_StarDestroyer.png" alt="Minecraft Star Destroyer">
&lt;em>Star Destroyer out of Star Wars - By Blade695&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I prefer the Destiny, you can&amp;rsquo;t forget the good old Star Destroyer, it brings back memories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Website Stumbling</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-08-02-free-website-stumbling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-08-02-free-website-stumbling/</guid><description>Recently I went on an adventure to buy a domain name, rent a server and build my own website. After being with free hosting for the last couple of years, I was fed up with the MySQL database outages and DoS attacks on the servers. So it was finally time to move up to paid hosting. If you ever do want to have a crack at making your own website with a budget of $0 the best hosts/domains from my experience were;</description></item><item><title>Make that Game</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-06-13-make-that-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-06-13-make-that-game/</guid><description>When I first discovered the world of programming I wanted to go and make the next Battlefield or Age of Empires, just like the “Getting Started” tutorial warns you against. (Yeah if you missed it, it&amp;rsquo;s right at the top, under the Getting Started heading.)
After failing at that, I lowered my goals to a 2D RTS and a Retro Scrolling Shooter. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished either of them. This time it wasn&amp;rsquo;t due to my programming skills, it was because I still hadn&amp;rsquo;t got that message in the “Getting Started” tutorial I had read all those aeons ago.</description></item><item><title>Level 19 - Innoquous 4</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-05-16-level-19-innoquous-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 09:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-05-16-level-19-innoquous-4/</guid><description>NAL the creator of Mmm and MADDENING for iPhone recently released his newest title Innoqous 4 on PC. It&amp;rsquo;s his first title in 3D and makes Innoquous 4 the best in the gravity-flipping series.
The first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll probably notice is that it is his best looking game yet. Previous NAL games have focused on game play rather than graphics in the past. It also has a very nice soundtrack that blends nicely into the game play.</description></item><item><title>Game Maker 8.1 Lite</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-16-game-maker-8-1-lite-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 08:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-16-game-maker-8-1-lite-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>GameMaker 8.1 (Single word now) has received mixed reviews on the &lt;a href="http://gmc.yoyogames.com/">Game Maker Community&lt;/a>, while a lot of members have given it thumbs up, many are upset that it has broken their code and is not compatible with certain extensions/DLLs. Personally though not only does it run all my games perfectly, it also runs them &lt;em>a lot&lt;/em> faster than Game Maker 8.0 (Two Words).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.yoyogames.com/">YoYo Games&lt;/a> made lots of noise about the new zoom feature in the room editor, while this is great (bit buggy though), the big thing new feature for me has to be the upgraded font rendering! Now all my games have sharp as crystal text. When Mike Dailly first brought up the whole font improvement, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t get it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even tell the difference between the two images he put up comparing the new and the old. But now I get it and I am going to rush out and buy the standard edition tomorrow (Literally).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Howdy!</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-14-howdy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 06:22:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-14-howdy/</guid><description>Its been a while, hasn&amp;rsquo;t it? I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do a blog a few times now, but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to keep it going. So here goes attempt three!
Alright, onto the good stuff, other than this blog I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy working on a very cool new game. It&amp;rsquo;s still early days, but it&amp;rsquo;s shaping up to be interesting.
Currently in the process of increasing the graphics quality, something that was severely lacking in the last game.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://derme.coffee/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/page/about/</guid><description>G&amp;rsquo;day, mate!
I&amp;rsquo;m Chris, I enjoy Coffee, Game of Thrones and anything that can break the speed of light.
My passion is in Engineering where I have Bachelor of Engineering. I majored in Robotics and Mechatronics and graduated with Honours.
In the last few years I&amp;rsquo;ve published a few games, helped build open-source software and run a local film festival. Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve built flying robots and CnC Machines.</description></item></channel></rss>