<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 19 on Derme's Coffee</title><link>https://derme.coffee/categories/level-19/</link><description>Recent content in Level 19 on Derme's Coffee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 12:52:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://derme.coffee/categories/level-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Level 19 - Homeworld Remastered</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2015-02-26-level-19-homeworld-remastered/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 12:52:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2015-02-26-level-19-homeworld-remastered/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://derme.coffee/uploads/2015/02/2015-02-26_00001-624x351.jpg" alt="Homeworld">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have not been excited for a video game release for quite some time, but when this was announced I was excited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I played the original Homeworld in 1999 I loved it, even though I could never get past the 6&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->th&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> mission at the time, it’s a game that’s stuck with me since.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Level 19 - Chickens and Moles</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-03-05-level-19-chickens-and-moles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 23:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-03-05-level-19-chickens-and-moles/</guid><description>Chickens and Molesis the latest release from the team over at Wormintheworks. The game is available on iOS, Android, Windows Phone, Windows, Mac and Facebook. I ended up scoring myself an iOS promo code.
When I first saw this game all I could think of was Angry Birds, a game which has too many clones these days. However Chickens &amp;amp; Moles is a whole different type of gameplay to that of Angry Birds, one which you find yourself touching the screen to throw boulders at various objects in the hope of rescuing en-caged animals.</description></item><item><title>Level 19 - Innoquous 4</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-05-16-level-19-innoquous-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 09:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-05-16-level-19-innoquous-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://musings.nalgames.co.uk/">NAL&lt;/a> the creator of &lt;a href="http://sandbox.yoyogames.com/games/102116-mmm">Mmm&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/maddening/id400656418?mt=8">MADDENING&lt;/a> for iPhone recently released his newest title Innoqous 4 on PC. It&amp;rsquo;s his first title in 3D and makes Innoquous 4 the best in the gravity-flipping series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll probably notice is that it is his best looking game yet. Previous NAL games have focused on game play rather than graphics in the past. It also has a very nice soundtrack that blends nicely into the game play.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I have never really been a NALGames fan, I have always found his unique creations to be to very grinding, having to repeat levels over and over again without gain, and this is something that continues into I4. Especially with the challenge modes (How do you complete a level in 7s? I had trouble doing the level in a few minutes), but the thing for me was that this time I found the game just genuinely fun to play. This was because of some of the new features included in the game, how could you not like a game where the goal is to go “bunny hunting”?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>