<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Derme's Coffee</title><link>https://derme.coffee/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on Derme's Coffee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 16:23:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://derme.coffee/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unicolour</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-09-06-unicolour/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 16:23:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-09-06-unicolour/</guid><description>With the shut down of Twitpic I decided it was time to upload my GIFs somewhere else, all one of them. Unfortunately Twitter doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow GIFs over 3MB, so I had to upload it to YouTube instead, but better than it being lost forever.</description></item><item><title>Mint - Preview of the new 'Blue' Steam UI</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-08-13-mint-preview-of-the-new-blue-steam-ui/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 02:17:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2014-08-13-mint-preview-of-the-new-blue-steam-ui/</guid><description>The Steam Database posted some mock-ups of what the Steam store will look like with the new theme that is currently in development. Out of curiosity I wanted to know what the whole thing would look like inside the updated client (that is currently available in the beta channel).
All over I think when it&amp;rsquo;s finished it&amp;rsquo;ll be a nice improvement over the current one which is, in my opinion, a little ugly but immeasurably better than what it used to look like.</description></item><item><title>GMC Game Jam, GooglePlay, Future Projects</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-31-gmc-game-jam-googleplay-future-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 08:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2013-01-31-gmc-game-jam-googleplay-future-projects/</guid><description>At the start of this week I entered the 9th GameMaker Community Game Jam, my entry wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as it could of been, in the end I only spent a small amount time working on it. However I had a lot of laughs making it and got some really helpful feedback, which I&amp;rsquo;ll take with me when I go into the next Jam in three months.
You can go see the entry here.</description></item><item><title>Official Portal 2 Turret? Yes please.</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-09-16-official-portal-2-turret-yes-please/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2012-09-16-official-portal-2-turret-yes-please/</guid><description>Portal would have to be one of my favourite puzzle games of all time the others being Lemmings and Portal 2.
When Velociraptor proofing my place of dwelling, something I always wanted to include was a couple of Portal turrets, so I&amp;rsquo;m really hoping that Valve plan to start selling them on the adjacent self to the Weighted Companion Cubes.</description></item><item><title>Free Website Stumbling</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-08-02-free-website-stumbling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-08-02-free-website-stumbling/</guid><description>Recently I went on an adventure to buy a domain name, rent a server and build my own website. After being with free hosting for the last couple of years, I was fed up with the MySQL database outages and DoS attacks on the servers. So it was finally time to move up to paid hosting. If you ever do want to have a crack at making your own website with a budget of $0 the best hosts/domains from my experience were;</description></item><item><title>Make that Game</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-06-13-make-that-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-06-13-make-that-game/</guid><description>When I first discovered the world of programming I wanted to go and make the next Battlefield or Age of Empires, just like the “Getting Started” tutorial warns you against. (Yeah if you missed it, it&amp;rsquo;s right at the top, under the Getting Started heading.)
After failing at that, I lowered my goals to a 2D RTS and a Retro Scrolling Shooter. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished either of them. This time it wasn&amp;rsquo;t due to my programming skills, it was because I still hadn&amp;rsquo;t got that message in the “Getting Started” tutorial I had read all those aeons ago.</description></item><item><title>Howdy!</title><link>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-14-howdy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 06:22:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://derme.coffee/posts/2011-04-14-howdy/</guid><description>Its been a while, hasn&amp;rsquo;t it? I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do a blog a few times now, but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to keep it going. So here goes attempt three!
Alright, onto the good stuff, other than this blog I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy working on a very cool new game. It&amp;rsquo;s still early days, but it&amp;rsquo;s shaping up to be interesting.
Currently in the process of increasing the graphics quality, something that was severely lacking in the last game.</description></item></channel></rss>